好了  最后一箱  我准备好上大学了
Okay, one last box, and I'm ready for college.
宝贝  东西太多了
Sweetheart, this is a lot of stuff.
你应该知道不用把你的所有家当
You do realize, you don't have to take all of this stuff
都搬到宿舍吧
with you to your dorm room?
比如说这个  这是什么
Like this. What is this?
记得吗  我想不加安全轮骑单车
Remember? I wanted to ride my bike without training wheels,
像大孩子一样  而且我做到了
Like the big kids, and I did.
所以你奖励了这枚金牌给我
So you got me my very own gold medal.
亲爱的  这真的是很甜蜜的回忆
Oh, well, honey, that is-- that's a very sweet memory,
但你的宿舍只有那么大
But your dorm room is only so big.
你得留些东西在家里
You're gonna have to leave some of this stuff behind.
别听他的  亲爱的
Don't listen to him, darling.
每个人都需要自己的东西
Everybody needs their stuff.
听见没
See?
我的宝贝女儿要上大学了
My little girl is going to college.
仿佛就在昨天
Seems like just yesterday,
你还每晚帮她检查床底
you were checking under the bed every night,
跟她保证世上根本没有妖怪
promising her that monsters aren't real.
我说谎了  的确有妖怪
Well, I lied. Monsters are real.
就是新生宿舍的那些男生
They're the boys in her freshman dorm.
说到这个
Oh, speaking of which,
在阿丽克西斯离开之前  你是不是应该
before Alexis leaves, don't you think you should have the, uh,
跟她聊聊
talk with her?
你是指性教育吗  老妈  几年前就聊过了
You mean the sex talk? Mother, I covered that ages ago.
我获益匪浅
I learned so much.
我是说你和贝克特上床的事
I mean the you-and-Beckett sex talk.
妈  贝克特和我...
Mother, Beckett and I ar--
省省吧  理查德
Save it, Richard.
我知道那天早上我进来时
I knew the morning I walked in here
那可怜的丫头藏在...
and the poor girl was hiding in the--
你怎么知道的
How did you know that?
当妈都对这种事洞若观火好吧
Mothers know these things.
但我不希望哪天阿丽克西斯回到家
But I don't think you want Alexis to walk in unannounced
发现你和贝克特  出柜了
and find you and Beckett... out of the closet.
我说的"出柜"...
And by "Out of the closet"--
我知道你说的"出柜"是什么意思
I--no, I-I-I know what you mean by "Out of the closet."
好吧  所以..
Okay, so...
你不觉得应该告诉她吗
Don't you think you should tell her?
告诉我什么
Tell me what?
你告诉了阿丽克西斯
You told Alexis?
我也不想  我妈用她的绝地武士意念指使我的
I didn't want to. Mother used her jedi mind tricks on me.
她也知道了吗
She knows, too?
卡塞尔  她们知道这事的利害关系吗
Castle, do they realize what's at stake here?
如果阿丽克西斯告诉了蕾妮
Because if Alexis tells Lanie...
阿丽克西斯不会告诉蕾妮的
Alexis won't tell Lanie.
蕾妮会告诉埃斯波西托
Lanie's gonna tell Esposito,
埃斯波西托是肯定会告诉莱恩的
Esposito can't keep his mouth shut with Ryan,
而莱恩这个大嘴巴则会到处说
And Ryan's gonna blow it out of proportion,
那么盖茨就会知道了
and then Gates is gonna find out,
我们就不能再在一起工作了
and we won't be able to work together anymore.
相信我
Trust me.
她知道其中的利害关系
She knows what's at stake,
我们的秘密很安全
and our secret is safe.
她接受了吗
So how did she take it,
我们在一起的事
us being together?
她太专注于离家上学的事  连回应都没有
She was too preoccupied with her move to even comment.
真是太好笑了
I mean, it's ridiculous.
她打包了一箱又一箱的东西
She's got boxes and boxes of stuff,
很显然  样样东西都很重要
And apparently, all of it's important.
我们都需要自己的东西  卡塞尔
Yeah, well, we all need our stuff, castle.
我也有一箱又一箱的东西
I've got boxes and boxes of it.
有安慰的作用
It's comforting.
让我想起我的过去
It reminds me of my past.
你的叛逆过去吗
Your kinky past?
这个内容的也有一箱
I've got that box, too.
清洁人员今早发现了她
Housekeeping found her this morning.
死者叫温蒂·杜普利  25岁
Name's Wendy Dupree, 25 years of age,
胸部中枪
single gunshot to the chest
凶器为9毫米手枪
from a 9 millimeter.
不幸的是  她没有立即毙命
Unfortunately, she died slowly.
是啊  至少有时间写下"谎言"
Yeah, long enough to write the word "Lie."
看来凶手不是专业人士
So our killer wasn't a pro.
否则不会在她死之前离开
She wouldn't have been left breathing.
临终遗言  可这词是什么意思呢
A dying declaration, but what does it mean?
这事儿归你们管
Hey, that's your department.
有人对她说谎了吗
Well, did someone lie to her?
也有可能是凶手名字的首字母
Perhaps it's the killer's initials.
也许是语法错误
Maybe a grammatical error.
她本来想写的是过去时
She should've written "Lay."
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
被害人的钱包
Victim's wallet.
她可是远道而来被杀害了
She came a long way to get killed.
她是费城人
She's a Philly girl.
她到纽约多久了
How long was she here for?
前台说她是昨天下午一个人入住的
Front desk says she checked in yesterday afternoon alone.
她不是一个人
She wasn't alone.
她带了4千块"好朋友"
She brought 4,000 of her closest friends.
有这么多现金  怎么住这种破地方
That kind of cash, what's she doing in a dump like this?
好了  查查财务状况  看能发现什么
All right, run financials. See what you guys can find.
卡塞尔  你怎么想
Castle, what do you think?
我想  虽然我非常喜欢悬疑
I think, as much as I love a good mystery,
但她要是多留点有用的信息就好了
she could've left a more helpful note.
这条短信不用解释什么了
Here's a message that needs no interpretation.
"你以为可以骗我吗"
"You think you can lie to me?"
也许"谎言"就是指的这个
Maybe that's the lie.
"随你怎么逃  我一定会找到你让你付出代价"
"Run all you want. I'm gonna find you and make you pay."
区号215  费城号码
It's a 2-1-5 area code. That's Philly.
申请搜查令调查手机
Pull a warrant for the cell phone.
我要知道是谁发的短信
I want to know who sent that text.
是我发的  当然是我
Yeah, I sent it. You bet I did.
听起来你跟她问题不小啊
Well, it sounds like you had a big problem with her.
那是当然了  问题大着呢
Hell, yeah, I had a problem.
温蒂在我那里做服务员  乔家芝士牛排三明治
Wendy's a waitress at my place, Joel's cheesesteaks--
费城最好的
The best in Philly.
费城最好  真像不知天高地厚的小孩的厥词
"The best in Philly"? That's a tad presumptuous.
本来就是
Well, it is.
昨天我派这个骗子去银行
So yesterday I sent that fraud to the bank
把餐馆的收入存起来
to make a deposit for the restaurant, right?
可她存了吗  没有
But does she make the drop? No.
她带着我的4千美金逃到了这里
She hightails it up here with 4,000 of my dollars.
那得卖好多三明治才能赚到
That's a lot of cheesesteak.
所以你追踪她到纽约  想取回你的钱
So you followed her to New York to get your money back.
那是当然  我想和气地解决这事
Damn right. I tried to be nice.
终于  她给我打电话了
Finally, she calls me,
她说  抱歉  我有急用
And she's like, "I'm sorry. It was an emergency.
等我回来一定双倍偿还
I'll pay you back double when I get back."
去她妈的  她竟然偷我的钱
Screw that. She stole from me.
就因为那样  她就该死吗
And for that, she deserved to die?
是啊
Yeah.
等等  什么
Wait. What?
不
Oh, no.
No.
不是我干的
I didn't do this.
不  我都没找到她
Nah. I couldn't even find her.
不  我刚从费城开来的火车上下来
No, I-I just got off the train from Philly, uh,
差不多1小时后就被你们找过来了
an hour before yous guys picked me up.
火车公司证实普拉特昨天的确买了票
So amtrak confirms that Pratt was ticketed yesterday,
但他们不确定他乘坐的是哪一趟车
but they can't be sure of what train he was on.
所以我们在复查他的不在场证明
So we're double-checking his alibi.
让他们顺便查查那家的三明治
Have them check on that cheesesteak, too.
那不可能是费城最棒的
There's no way that it's the best in philly.
总之  就算是他
Anyway, even if it was him,
也无法解释温蒂的神秘急事
it doesn't explain Wendy's mysterious emergency--
她偷钱
The stolen cash,
又突然来到纽约
the sudden trip to New York city.
她为什么要写"谎言"
Why she would write "Lie."
没人会在临死前用血随便写点东西开玩笑
You don't write a dying message in blood just for kicks.
肯定是有什么隐情的
There had to be a reason.
你也喝完了吗  要再来一点吗
Are you out, too? Want some more?
是啊  这次还是我去倒吧
Yeah. Uh, you know what? I'll go get it.
谢谢
Thank you.
长岛特快列车
Long Island expressway.
卓越文人的殿堂
Literary institute of excellence.
爱是一切
Love is everything.
噢  我刚说了这句吗
Oh, did I just say that?
我真是变得柔情似水啊
I'm getting soft.
贝克特探长专线
Detective Beckett's phone.
卡塞尔
Castle?
你不能接贝克特的电话的
You're not allowed to answer Beckett's phone.
我可以的
Yes, I am.
从什么时候开始的
Since when?
从我...
Since I...
请问你打来是有什么事吗
Can--is there something I can do for you?
是的  你拿笔记一下
Yeah. Write this down.
我从现场取回来的弹壳上发现了部分指纹
I've got a partial off the shell casing.
在系统中查不到对应的
No matches in the system
和普拉特先生的也不符
or to Mr. Pratt,
但我确实发现了一些DNA残留
But I did find some trace D.N.A.
你在记吗
Are you writing this down?
-是的  -卡塞尔
- Yes. - Castle.
好吧  稍等一下
Okay, hang on.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
哎呀  你要有麻烦了
Ooh. You are in trouble.
我不会有麻烦的
I'm not in trouble.
蕾妮发现了部分指纹
Lanie got a partial print.
跟普拉特的不符  他不是我们要找的凶手
It is not a match for Pratt. He is not our guy.
谁说你可以替我接电话啊
Who said that you could answer my phone?
你又为什么要翻我的抽屉
And why are you going through my drawers?
我只是在找张纸记东西罢了
I was just looking for a pad of paper.
说得好听  别碰我的东西  卡塞尔
Sure you were. Stay out of my stuff, Castle.
你的东西
Your stuff?
需要我提醒你一下吗
Need I remind you,
我已经见过你的"东西"了
I've already seen your stuff.
是啊  但我的有些东西还是隐私的
Yeah, well, some of my stuff is still private.
好吧  我懂了
Oh, I get it.
-肯定是老情人做了送给你的  -不是
- An old boyfriend made that for you. - No.
是吗  没关系啊  我不会吃醋的
Really? 'cause it's totally cool. I wouldn't be jealous.
好吧  或许会有点吃醋
Okay, maybe a little bit jealous.
-不是老情人吗  -不是
- Not an old boyfriend? - Mnh-mnh.
那你一定是从犯罪现场得到的
You got it from a crime scene.
那是个纪念品
That is a keepsake
纪念你破获的第一桩案件
from the first murderer you ever collared.
我告诉过你  卡塞尔
I told you, Castle,
那是个人隐私
It's private.
也可能是火柴人年会上
Maybe it's the actual murder victim
某个受害的火柴人
from a stick man convention.
不是吧你
Really?
你只能想出这种程度的烂故事了吗
That's the best that you can come up with?
-接受挑战  -那个...
- Challenge accepted. - So...
从温蒂的财务账单上
Nothing in the financials
无法看出她为什么需要4千现金
explain why Wendy needed 4 grand in cash,
但我差不多知道她来这儿的目的了
But I might have figured out what she was doing in town.
她昨天刷了信用卡
She used her credit card
乘车去了第8大道和市场街
for a cab ride to 8th and market yesterday.
就是她死的当天
The day she was killed.
我跟一个出租车司机谈过  温蒂拿了他的名片
I spoke with a cabbie. Wendy took his business card.
说她会给他打电话
Said she was going to call
让他今天再送她过去
to have him take her back there today.
我敢说那里会有我们想要的答案
Bet we find our answer there.
自储式仓库
A self-storage warehouse?
一个从费城来的姑娘到这儿来干什么
What's a girl from Philly doing in a place like this?
是的  是的
Oh, yeah, yeah.
她来过这里
She was here.
不过我见到她的时候身上可没这么多血
A lot less bloody when I saw her, though.
她报了名参加拍卖
She signed up for the auction.
拍卖
Auction?
我们每个月都会拍售被占用的储物仓库
Every month we auction off repossessed storage units.
就是那些赖账的
You know, from deadbeats
他们没有付账
That don't pay their bills.
现在就有场拍卖会正在进行呢
There's one going on right now.
那4千块就是为了这个
That's what the $4,000 was for.
她想拍下一间储物仓库
She was gonna bid on a unit.
哪一间呢
Which unit?
问倒我了
Beats me.
可能是我们打算拍售的14间中的任何一间
Could be any one of the 14 we got up for bid.
所以完全不知道她对哪间有兴趣
So there's no way of telling which one she was interested in?
其实  是有线索的
Actually, there is a way.
我们错误地理解了温蒂留下的信息
We misinterpreted Wendy's message.
那写的不是"谎言"
It's not "Lie."
我们把它看倒了
We were looking at it upside down.
应该是3-1-7  这才是她想说的
It's "3-1-7." That's what she was trying to say.
317号仓库在这次拍卖中吗
Is unit 317 up for auction?
哦  还真在
Oh, as a matter of fact, it is.
没准我们说话这会儿它已经拍卖出去了
Probably auctioning it off as we speak.
温蒂想买下这间仓库结果却被杀了
Wendy was killed trying to buy that unit.
如果我们让它白白被卖掉
If we let it get sold off...
那我们就失去找出凶手的好机会了
Then we'll lose our best shot at finding out who the killer is.
好  下一个  317号仓库
Okay, next up is unit 317.
你们有一分钟的时间参观  然后开始竞拍
You have 60 seconds to look, and then we start the bidding.
莱恩  这间仓库的所有者名叫约翰·弗莱明
All right, Ryan, so the owner of the unit was a Johan Fleming.
你能查一下吗
Can you run that?
好  谢了
Okay, thanks.
我们需要你停止这次拍卖
We need you to stop this auction.
虽然我想帮忙  但是我更想赚钱
As much as I'd like to help, I'd like my money more.
所以你如果没有搜查令  我就不会阻止杰克
So unless you got a warrant, I don't have to stop jack.
好  还有30秒
Okay, 30 seconds.
卡塞尔  你看见什么了
Castle, what do you see?
没看见什么
Uh... not much.
只是
Just a...
只是一堆垃圾
Just a bunch of junk.
可这堆垃圾里可能有温蒂案子的关键线索
Yeah, well, the key to Wendy's murder might be in that junk,
而我们却要错过了
And we're about to lose it.
我来不及去搞搜查令了
There's no way I can get a warrant in time.
搞不到也没关系  我有更好的东西
You may not have a warrant, but I got something better.
支票本
Checkbook.
拍卖只接受现金  炫富男
Auctions are cash only, hotshot.
不是吧
Oh, no.
我们肿么办  两千够吗
What are we gonna do? Is 2 grand enough?
你兜里带着两千大洋干嘛
What are you doing with 2 grand in your pocket?
我可是畅销作家
I'm a best-selling author.
随身不带个两千怎么行
Why wouldn't I have 2 grand in my pocket?
好了  你们愿意花多少钱呢
All right. What do you want to give for it?
谁来抢第一拍  一百元起拍
Who'll start us out? $100 bid.
-谁愿意出一百  -这里
- Who's gonna go $100 one time? - Right here.
一百元  谁愿意出价两百  出价两百
$100. Now who'll go $200? $200. $200 bid now.
-这里  -两百  谢谢  非常感谢
- Yep, yep. $200, thank you. Thank you very much.
有谁加价到三百吗  有人吗
Now who's gonna go to $300? Looking for a $300 bid.
我出三百元
I got $300 on it.
大个子波西出价三百  有人出价四百吗
Big Percy's in for $300. Now who wants to go $400?
-这里  -有人多过四百吗  四百一次
- Right here. - Who's going $400? One time.
帅小子抢回主动权  压过四百
Pretty boy's back, and he's in for $400.
弗兰基出价五百  有人出六百吗
Frankie's got $500. Now who's gonna go $600?
-六百  -这里
- $600-- - Yep, yep.
佩吉出价六百  非常感谢
Peggy's in for $600. Thank you very much.
- 有人出价七百吗  - 我加一百
-Now who's gonna go $700? $700 - Next 100.
七百  非常感谢  有人出八百吗
$700. Thank you very much. Who's gonna go $800?
-有人愿意再加一百吗  -我出八百
- Who's going $800 one time? - I got $800 on it.
大个子波西出价八百  有人出九百吗
Big Percy's got $800. Now who's gonna go $900?
弗兰基出价九百  现在等待一千的出现
Frankie's got $900. Now looking for a $1,000 bid.
有人加价到一千吗
Who's going $1,000 one time?
有人愿意出价一千吗
Do I hear $1,000 from anybody here?
一次加价到一千元
Go a $1,000 bid one time.
-一千五  -一千五
- $1,500. - $1,500.
有人出价更高吗
Anybody gonna top that?
还有人吗  一千五百元一次
Anybody anywhere? $1,500 going once.
一千五百元两次
$1,500 going twice.
一千六
$1,600.
甜蜜十六岁最后时刻及时出现
Sweet 16 gets in just under the wire.
有人出价一千七吗
Now who's gonna go $1,700?
还有人继续出价吗  愿意出一千七的
Want to go $1,700 one time? Want to go $1,700?
还有人愿意出价一千七吗  还有人吗
Looking for a $1,700 bid. Anybody for $1,700?
我只有两千元
I've only got $2,000.
这里
Here.
签名
Sign it.
竞拍还在继续
Now keep bidding.
你好呀
Hi. Hi.
大个子波西  对吧
Big Percy, right?
怎样才能给我你身上所有现金呢
What would it take to get all the cash you have on you?
就看你给我什么了
Depends on what you offering.
明星签名怎么样
How about a check?
绝对好的交易  我保证
No, it's good. I swear.
由百万富翁悬疑小说家理查德·卡塞尔签出
It's signed by the millionaire mystery novelist Richard Castle.
说的跟真的似的
Yeah, right.
真的  他就站在我后面呢
No, really. He's right behind me.
-真人真身  -当然
- For real? - Yeah.
我妈妈爱死他的书了  我乐意
My moms loves his books. Yes. I'll do it.
好
Okay.
我给你一千六
I'll give you $1,600.
但是你得给我两千五
But it'll cost $2,500.
-一千八  -两千三
- $1,800. - $2,300.
两千  并且在下本书里以你妈的名字
2 grand, and he'll name a character in his next novel
-命名个角色  -什么
- after your mom. - What?
成交
Sold.
给你  谢了
Here you go. Thanks.
我们有三千六  不成功便成仁
We got $3,600. Now make it work.
有人出价两千零五十吗  加到两千零五十
Who'll go to 24 and a half? Give me 24 and a half one time.
-看好了  -两千五
- Watch this. - $2,500 one time.
你说什么  出价两千五
What do you say? Give me $2,500.
有人出价多过两千五吗
Do I hear $2,500 anywhere?
-三千  -三千
- $3,000. - $3,000...
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
相信我  我能搞定
Trust me. I got this.
加价到三千一
Go $3,100 one time.
我觉得他会买下  有人出价三千一吗
I think he might buy it. Who'll go $3,100?
三千零五十
$3,050.
三千零五十  你愿意出价三千一吗
$3,050. Now you want to go $3,100?
你愿意加价到三千一吗  快决定
You go $3,100 one time? Let me hear it.
你要加价到三千一吗  怎么样
You want to go $3,100 one time? What do you say?
三千五
$3,500.
三千五  你想加价到三千六吗
$3,500. Now you want to go $3,600?
开塞尔  我们只有三千六
Castle, we've only got $3,600.
下次加价三千五百五  三千五百五
Go 35 and a half. Go 35 and a half.
你知道吗  我一天都能玩这个
You know what? I can do this all day.
我自己加价  三千六
I'll outbid myself. $3,600.
三千六
$3,600.
有人出价更高吗
Anybody gonna top that?
有人吗  三千六一次
Anybody where? $3,600 going once.
三千六两次  尽快竞拍过时不候
$3,600 going twice. Bid now or forever hold your peace.
帅小子以三千六百元赢得竞拍
Sold right there to pretty boy for $3,600.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
你怎么知道这招能行
How did you even know that was gonna work?
作为一名赌王
Well, as a champion poker player,
我可是研究过肢体语言的
I am a student of body language.
只要看他一眼我就能判断出
I could tell easily by looking at him--
你根本是瞎蒙的
You had absolutely no idea.
的确是
Not a clue.
祝贺你
Congrats.
那些废品都归你了
All that junk is yours.
是的  谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
对了  我母亲的名字是
Oh, and, uh, my mother's name...
尤妮丝
is Eunice.
借过
Excuse me.
尤妮丝
Eunice?
哥们儿  这堆破烂真是你花钱买的吗
Damn, bro. You actually bought all this crap?
这堆玩意儿能帮我们打开突破口
All this crap is gonna crack this case wide open.
谢谢你  中尉
Thank you, L.T.
你这次可欠了我一个大人情
You are so going to owe me for this.
卡塞尔  我不知道警局能不能
Castle, I don't know if the department's
给你报销这次的花费
gonna be able to reimburse you for all of this.
我指的不是这个
That's not the owing I mean.
查过了317号仓库的主人
Ran down the name on unit 317--
约翰·弗莱明
Johan Fleming.
登记的地址是假的  名字也是假的
Address is bogus. Name is bogus.
根本就没这么个人
The guy doesn't exist.
那这些东西是谁的
Then whose stuff is this?
答案就摆在我们面前
Well, the answer's right in front of us.
他的这些东西会告诉我们主人是谁
His stuff will tell us who he is.
瞧  这有一叠地图
Look, there's a box of maps.
他是个地理爱好者
Um, he was a geography buff.
他喜欢旅行
He enjoyed travel.
或许是个卡车司机
Maybe he was a trucker.
看到了吗  有进展了
Ah. See? Progress.
攀岩装备
Ooh. Yo, climbing gear.
他还是个野外运动家
He's an outdoorsman.
一个变态的野外运动家
A super creepy outdoorsman.
卡塞尔  这都是高档货
Hey, this is high-end stuff, Castle.
能送给我吗
Can I have this?
不行
No.
为什么不行  你又不攀岩
Why not? You're not a climber.
我花了大价钱买这些东西
I spent a lot of money on this stuff.
你想要  给钱吧
You want something? Make me an offer.
这边怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
这些废品是谁的
Whose junk is this,
怎么会出现在我的警局里
And what in the hell is it doing in my precinct?
都是卡塞尔的  长官
It's Castle's, sir.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
长官  实际上
Uh, sir, actually,
这跟我们正在调查的案子有关
it's a part of an ongoing investigation.
我不管  把它们给我全部都处理掉
I don't care. I want it gone, all of it.
那是
Is that...
还真是
Oh, it is.
你知道你手里拿的是什么吗
Do you know what you have?
你知道它多稀有吗
How rare that piece is?
长官
Sir?
你收藏这东西吗
Are you a collector?
从小就开始了
Ever since I was a kid.
我找这个东西
I have searched...
已经好几年了
for years.
那么
Well...
别再找了  送给你
Search no more.
-不会吧  -真的
- No. - Yes.
它是你的了
It's yours.
真的吗
Really? Well,
我都不知道该...
I --I don't know w--I--
接受了吧
Say you'll accept.
谢谢你
Thank you.
太谢谢你了
Thank you very much.
你们继续
Uh... carry on.
你能把东西送她就不能送给我
Oh, you can give her something, but you can't give me something?
对  反正你已经是我这伙的了
Yeah, you already like me.
伙计们  有发现
Hey, guys. Mother lode.
报税单
Tax returns.
看来约翰·弗莱明的真名叫温德尔·杜普利
Looks like Johan Fleming's actually Wendell Dupree.
跟死者的姓是一样的
That's the same last name as our victim.
出生日期也一样  他们一定是双胞胎
Yes, and the same date of birth, too. They must be twins.
等等  双胞胎
Wait. Twins.
当然了  这就全讲得通了
Of course. It all makes sense now.
温德尔的假名字  约翰·弗莱明
Wendell's secret identity-- Johan Fleming--
和Zan的假名字一样
Is the same secret identity of Zan,
就是
The male half
超人双胞胎中的那个男胎
Of the wonder twins.
超人双胞胎
Wonder twins?
《超人联盟》
The Super Friends?
没搞错吧  伙计们
Seriously, you guys,
你们不看电视吗
Do you not watch TV?
如果这间仓库是她兄弟的
If this unit belonged to her brother,
那为什么温蒂还要去竞拍呢
then why was Wendy bidding on it?
他为什么不再付租金了呢
Why did he stop making payments?
还有他为什么要用假名字呢
And why was he using an alias?
我们还是先找到温德尔然后问他吧
Why don't we track down Wendell and ask him?
你们还是先买台电视吧
Why don't you buy a TV?
谁能想到盖茨警监还有温柔的一面
Who knew that Gates had a softer side?
天啊  太漂亮了
Oh, god. Just beautiful.
有点
It's, um...
瘆人  非常非常瘆人
Creepy, very, very... creepy.
她兄弟查的怎么样了
So where are we on the brother?
他俩的生活很艰辛
Oh, it turns out the twins had a hard knock life.
父母在他们小的时候
Their parents died in a car crash
死于车祸
when they were teens.
温德尔似乎一直没能从伤痛中走出来
It's like Wendell never really fully recovered.
他不停地搬家  干些违法的事
He moved from town to town, getting in scrapes with the law.
那我们去哪找他呢
So where can we find him?
墓地里
In an urn.
他6周前死了
He died six weeks ago.
被地铁撞死了
Hit by a subway train.
真惨
Ouch.
这就解释了他为什么不再付仓库租金了
Explains why his storage bill wasn't paid.
报告里说那是意外事故吗
It says here it was an accident?
地铁里的监控器坏了
Well, the subway cameras were broken,
所以无法证实了
so there's really no way to know for sure.
如果他的死和温蒂的死有关
If his death is related to Wendy's,
这可能是又一起谋杀案
we could be looking at a second murder.
刚刚联系了温蒂在费城的
Okay, so that was one of Wendy's
服务员同事
fellow waitresses from Philly.
据她所说  温蒂确信
According to her, Wendy was convinced
她弟弟并非死于意外
that her brother's death wasn't an accident.
显而易见  他陷入了某种危险中
Apparently, he was involved in something dangerous.
哪种危险
What kind of dangerous?
温蒂没说  不过据这位服务员所说
Wendy didn't say, but according to this waitress,
就在地铁意外前夕  温德尔打给他姐姐
just before the subway accident, Wendell called his sister
说事情已经结束
and said it was over and
所有的麻烦也已烟消云散
all of their problems were solved.
只不过  弟弟最终以死收场
And yet, he ends up dead
姐姐绝望到不惜冒一切风险
and she was desperate enough to risk everything--
丢工作  下监狱
her job, jail--
只为了找她弟弟的储物仓库
just to go after her brother's storage unit.
为什么呢
Why?
这些东西我们都查过了
I mean, we've been through all this stuff,
看起来就是堆不知所谓的废品
it just seems like a bunch of random junk.
也许只是
Well, maybe it's just that
我们还不清楚到底要找什么
we don't know exactly what we're looking for.
无论是谁杀了温蒂
I mean, whoever killed Wendy
极有可能是温德尔认识的人
most likely came from Wendell's world.
我们掌握了他的什么线索
So what do we know about him?
过去的三个月里  温德尔一直用化名
For the last three months, using his wonder twin alias,
给一个叫安吉莉卡·亨利的人
Wendell worked as a chauffer
当司机
for one Angelica Henley,
她是个有权有势的贵妇
a wealthy socialite.
好
Okay.
我们就从这查起
Then let's start here.
晚上好
Good evening.
能为你们效劳吗
May I help you?
我们想找亨利夫人谈谈
Uh, we were hoping to speak with Ms. Henley.
身穿紫色酒会礼服的女士就是了
The lady in the purple cocktail dress.
需要我引荐吗
May I take you to her?
我们自己去就行了
Uh, you know what? I think we can manage.
要香槟吗
Champagne?
我在工作呢
I'm on duty.
一声叹息  我只好独饮了
Ah, alas, I'm forced to drink alone.
安吉莉卡·亨利
Angelica Henley.
是安赫莉卡
Anhelica.
里面的G不发音
The "G" Is silent.
那不就是安莉卡了吗
Wouldn't that make it Anelica?
是安赫莉卡
Anhelica.
我是凯特·贝克特探长
Well, I'm Detective Kate Beckett,
这位是卡塞尔先生
And this is Mr. Castle.
我们能谈谈吗
Could we have a word?
究竟所为何事  我还有客人
What's all this about? I have guests.
我知道您雇了一位叫约翰·弗莱明的人
Now I understand that you employed a man named Johan Fleming.
是的  可怜的孩子死的时候我心都碎了
Yes, and I was so heartbroken when the poor boy died.
您知道他的真名叫温德尔·杜普利吗
Well, were you aware that his real name was Wendell Dupree?
我不知道
No, I wasn't.
他有没有什么仇家
Did he have any enemies?
没有  我不这么认为
No, I-I don't think so.
慢着  你说他叫温德尔
Wait. You mean, his-- his name was Wendell?
他是不是惹了麻烦
Was he in trouble?
还是参与了什么不法活动
Was he involved in any illegal activities.
不  没有  警察已经给他澄清了
No, no, no. The police cleared him.
澄清什么
Of what?
他死的前两天  我遭劫了
Oh, well, two days before he died, I was robbed.
有人闯进了我家  撬了我的壁式保险箱
Somebody broke in here and cracked my wall safe.
劫匪拿走了什么
What did they take?
我那条用粉钻打造的手镯
My bracelet made out of pink diamonds
价值可是超过了四百万美元
that was worth over $4 million.
温德尔偷了那条手镯
Wendell stole the bracelet.
就放在储物仓库里
That's what's in the storage unit.
这就是他命丧黄泉的原因
That's why he was killed.
你有什么好欣喜若狂的
What are you so happy about?
有条价值四百万美元的钻石手链
There is a $4-million diamond bracelet
就在我赢回的拍卖品中
buried in my auction winnings.
我发达了
I'm rich.
或者更发达了
Or richer.
直到贝克特探长从你这里拿走
Till Detective Beckett takes it from you
归还给真正的物主
and returns it to its rightful owner.
也对  不过这也破坏不了我的好心情
Yes, but not even that can ruin my day
因为今晚
because tonight
是和我女儿
is my very special
临上大学前的送别晚餐
last-night-before-college dinner with my daughter.
关于这事  我们取消好吗
About that. Can we cancel?
什么  你说什么  为什么
What? Whoa. What? Why?
阿丽克西斯  我们几个月前就计划好了
Alexis, we made these plans months ago.
你知道即便是你爸我
Do you know how hard it is, even for me,
能订到位子有多不容易吗
to get reservations--
你要是这么在意预订的位子
If it's the reservations you care so much about,
不如带你的女朋友去好了
why don't you just take your girlfriend?
等一下  阿丽克西斯  我不是
Hold on, Alexis. That's not...
我不是
That's not--
我不是那个意思
that's not what I meant.
阿丽克西斯讨厌我
Alexis hates me?
因为我们在一起了
Is it because we're together?
我猜她可能觉得自己被取代了
I guess she feels like she's being replaced,
说来也怪
which is weird
她以前从不这样的
because she's never done this before--
对吉娜不会
not with Gina,
对我以前成群的超正女友都不会
not with the hundreds of super-hot girlfriends I've--
行了  我不想听
Okay, I don't need to hear this.
好吧
Right.
你觉得我该跟她谈谈吗
So do you think I should talk to her?
不  不行
No, no, no, no.
不行  她会把你给生吞活剥了
No, she'll eat you alive.
我来处理吧
Let me handle it.
处理什么
Handle what?
-没什么  -没什么
- Nothing.  - Nothing.
警员在彻查温德尔所有的遗物
So... uniforms are going through Wendell's belongings,
想找到手镯
looking for the bracelet,
不过盗窃科终于把安吉莉卡·亨利家
but Robbery finally sent over the report
入室抢劫案的报告送过来了
on the break-in on Angelica Henley's.
看看这个
Take a look at these.
美艳绝伦
Wow. A real beauty.
绝对值得为它去杀人
Certainly worth killing for.
未免某人胡思乱想
I am speaking of the bracelet
声明一下我说的是手镯
in case anyone is wondering.
是两人作案  经验老到
It was a 2-man job, pretty sophisticated, too.
嫌犯之一在地下室的警报器上装了旁路
One suspect put a bypass on the alarm in the basement.
另一个从屋顶沿绳而下
The other rappelled from the roof
从窗口进去
And went in through the window.
这就解释了那些攀爬器械存在的原因
Which explains the climbing equipment you had your eye on.
温德尔在偷走钻石手镯后
So Wendell was suspiciously hit by a train
很可疑地被火车撞死
after stealing a diamond bracelet,
六个星期之后
and then six weeks later,
他的妹妹试图寻找他的储物仓库
his sister goes looking for his storage unit,
结果也死了
and she ends up dead.
有没有可能是"盗亦无道"  自相残杀
What if it's a "no honor among thieves" thing?
你说过行窃需要两个人
You said it was a 2-man job.
有没有可能是温德尔的同伙
What if Wendell's partner decided
决定独吞手镯
that he wanted the bracelet for himself,
只是他在还没弄清温德尔
only he killed Wendell
藏匿手镯的地点就把他杀了
before he figured out where he'd stashed it?
所以他跟踪了温蒂  她领他到储物仓库
So he follows Wendy, she leads him to the storage unit,
他又把她杀了
and then he kills her.
找到同伙  就找到凶手了
Find the partner, find the killer.
也许我们已经找到他了
Well, maybe we already found him.
什么意思
What do you mean?
卡塞尔  你还记得竞拍时
Castle, do you remember at the auction,
所有竞价者在价格抬到1500美元时就放弃了竞拍
all of the bidders dropped out after $1,500?
除了那个人
Except one.
他知道里面有什么
He knew what was inside.
不然为什么会出那么高的价格
Why else would he bid so high?
菲利克斯·格泽林恩  纽约警局
Felix Gozarian, NYPD.
开门
Open up.
马上来
Just a second!
他要逃跑
He's making a run for it.
-撞吧  -纽约警局
- Yeah. Go. - NYPD!
纽约警局
NYPD!
别动
Don't move.
放下武器
Drop it.
我以为你们是来偷东西的贼
I thought you were thieves trying to steal my stuff.
我完全不知道那仓库里有什么
I had absolutely no idea what was in the storage unit. It's--
但你却异于他人
Yet, unlike anyone else there,
把价格抬得超高
you bid us through the roof.
小姐  那叫技巧  我竞拍过许多东西
Lady, that's strategy. I-I bid on a lot of things.
那是我的生财之道
That's how I make my money.
这么说你出售这些东西
So you actually... sell this stuff?
还没
Not yet.
我还在整货  记录分类
I'm still organizing, cataloging.
收集什么  竞拍什么
There's a method to all of this--
都是讲究方式方法的
you know, what I collect, what I bid on.
特别是在你有内线消息的时候
Especially when you got inside information.
你知道那仓库里有什么
You knew exactly what was in that unit.
不  我不知道
No, I didn't.
我想起
Yeah, you know, I was thinking,
当我报名参加竞拍的时候
when I signed up for the auction,
有个男人
there was a guy.
他出五百块钱请我替他
Yeah, offered me $500 to be his proxy,
去竞拍317号
get unit 317.
非常明确  就要317
Very specific. 317.
你怎么回答的
And what did you say?
我拒绝了
I said no.
就五百块  我不缺那点钱
$500? I'm not in for the short money.
但这使我很好奇
It made me curious.
为什么非要317
317. Why?
那人应该就是温德尔的同伙
That was probably Wendell's partner.
他在竞拍现场吗
And was he at the auction?
不  不在  我后来再没见过他
No. No, no, no, no. I never saw him again.
我们要带你回去见见人像画师
We're gonna need you to sit with a sketch artist.
菲利克斯的不在场证明成立
So Felix alibied out.
但是
But...
这是谁
Who's that?
温德尔的同伙
Wendell's partner.
莱恩和埃斯波西托正在查他的身份信息
Ryan and Esposito are trying to I.D. him now.
你有什么进展
How about you?
我已经翻遍了
I have ripped through
这里所有能装下手镯的东西
everything in this room big enough to hide a bracelet.
猜我找到了什么
You know what I found?
-什么都没找到  -什么都没有
- Nothing? - Absolutely nothing.
除了这个双节棍
Save for these wicked nunchakus,
我用它敲开热狗机
which is how I broke the hot dog maker.
还有一些名著  《斯洛伐克波尔卡舞曲》
Also some notable books-- Slovakian Polka Music,
《人工眼球制造》和我的最爱
Prosthetic Eye Manufacturing, and my favorite,
《爱尔兰旅者的历史》
a "History of Irish Travelers."
我不懂
I don't get it.
这些证据  杀死温蒂的凶手
All of the evidence, Wendy's murder--
一切线索都显示
everything points to the fact that
手镯就在仓库里
that bracelet should be in there.
但是它不在
Well, it's not.
但在这期间  我想出了一些
I did, however, make some headway
关于你的那个小棍人的故事
on my little stick man theory.
是吗
Really?
是的  当你还是制服警员的时候
Yes. Whilst you were still an officer,
你曾不顾自身危险  冲入车流
you risked your life running into traffic
救了一个吉普赛老妪
to save an old gypsy woman.
一个吉普赛女人
A gypsy woman?
吉普赛老妪
An old gypsy woman.
为了奖励你的英勇
To reward your bravery,
她给了你一个护身符
she gave you a talisman.
她说  只要你带着它
She said, as long as you keep it.
你就不会受到伤害
No harm will ever befall you.
我就不会受到伤害
No harm will ever befall me?
我觉得你看起来挺健全的呀
You look all right to me.
卡塞尔先生
So, Mr. Castle,
我决定拜读你的《冰冻希特》
I decided to give "Frozen Heat" a read,
你知道吗
and you know what?
真是本好书
It's really a good book.
你喜欢吗
You liked it?
我爱死了
I loved it.
-你介意签个名吗  -不
- I, uh, do you mind? - No.
我已经订购了妮基·希特系列其他的几本
I-I ordered the rest of the Nikki Heat series.
再次感谢你
And, again, thank you
把娃娃送给我
for my gemini collectible.
现在我的收藏完整了
I now have a complete set.
看见了吗
You see that?
现在她爱死我了
She loves me now,
这都要感谢那个阴森森的小娃娃
and I've got that scary little monstrosity to thank for it.
伙计们  来看看这个
Hey, guys. You need to see this.
抢劫组的同事查过一个叫马可·温斯特利的人
So robbery interviewed a guy named Marco Vinstrolli.
安吉莉卡手镯被偷的那晚  他在那个街角
His van got a parking ticket around the corner
得到一张违规停车的罚单
the night that Angelica's bracelet was stolen.
现在还无法将他和案子联系起来  但是
Now they found nothing to connect him, but...
很像吧
Look familiar?
就是他
That's our guy.
仓库管理员说在拍卖的前一天
The storage manager said that he rented Marco a unit
他租给马可同一层的一个单元
on the same floor the day before the auction.
于是我过了一遍监控录像
So I-I reviewed their surveillance tapes.
这是昨天早上六点的录像
This is from 6:00 a.m. yesterday morning.
也就是拍卖前的五小时
Five hours before the auction.
他闯进了我的储物仓库
He broke into my storage unit.
好吧  那时还是温德尔的
Well, it's--it was Wendell's at the time,
但现在是我的
but now it's mine.
那是保险箱吗
Is that a safe?
正是如此我们才找不到你的手镯
That's why we couldn't find your bracelet.
因为它在保险箱里
Because it was in the safe.
我的保险箱
My safe.
拿到对那车的搜查证了吗
So do we have a license on that van?
放下手中的东西
Put it down, dirtbag!
纽约警察  立刻举起双手
NYPD, put up your hands right now!
马可  立刻放下你的工具
Take your hand off your tool, Marco.
不许说话
Shut up.
马可  我们知道你和温德尔曾是搭档
Marco, we know that you and Wendell were partners.
你们行窃的时候  车被贴了罚单
Your van was ticketed when you guys pulled the job.
劫案组之前没法证明
Robbery couldn't prove it before,
但是现在我们掌握了这些  所以抓到你了
but now with these, well, we got you.
在我看来你们抓我似乎只是因为
Well, it seems to me like all you've got me for
我偷了保险箱
is stealing a safe.
这能判多长时间啊  30天吗
What's the punishment for that, 30 days?
等我们加上
More like 30 years
温德尔和温蒂的谋杀指控后  我看30年还差不多
after we add Wendell and Wendy's murders to it.
谋杀
Murder?
我还是老实招供吧
Why don't you tell us exactly what happened,
我们会让地检官给你提供减罪协议
and we'll get the D.A. to cut you a deal?
但是你最好抓紧点
But you better hurry,
因为他们正在切开那个保险箱
because they're cutting through that safe,
一旦他们发现了钻石手镯
and when they find that diamond bracelet,
你怎么求情都没用
you're on your own.
你知道我喜欢这案子哪点吗
You know what I love about this case?
哪点
What's that?
在我的物品里寻找漂亮的粉色手镯
Finding a pretty pink bracelet in my belongings.
你知道我们得把它还给
You know you're gonna have to return that--
我知道  莱恩
I know, Ryan.
我知道
I know that.
你就不能让我享受
Can't you just let me have this moment,
这个《金银岛》混搭
this one small, "Treasure island,"
《夺宝奇兵》的时刻吗
Indiana Jones moment?
抱歉  知道了
Sorry. You got it.
太晚了  已经被你毁了
Well, it's too late now. It's ruined.
我只是帮助他闯入那个阁楼
All I did was help him break in to that penthouse.
我发誓
I swear to god,
我都不认识那个人
I didn't even know the guy.
约翰或是温德尔
Johan or Wendell,
管他叫什么  给了我五千美金
whatever, paid me 5 grand
关掉报警器  什么问题都不问
to kill the alarms, no questions asked.
我们成功后  他很高兴
We did the job, he came out happy,
说"任务完成"  我们就分道扬镳了
said "Mission accomplished," we went separate ways.
可是你还是想要那个手镯
Except you still wanted the bracelet.
所以你就杀了他
So you went after him and you killed him.
我根本都不知道他拿走了那个该死的手镯
I didn't even know that he took that damn bracelet
直到我在报纸上看到
until I read about it in the papers.
那时候他已经死了
And by that time, he was already dead.
所以我就闯入温德尔家
So I broke into Wendell's,
但我只找到一把标记着"储物仓库"的钥匙
but all I found was a key, marked "Storage unit."
但你不知道储物仓库在哪
And you didn't know where that storage unit was.
所以我就密切关注即将举办的拍卖
So I kept a close eye on upcoming auctions
后来我就找到了写着约翰名字的
until I found one with Johan's name.
我一看到里面的保险箱我就知道
As soon as I saw the safe inside, I knew...
他将钻石手镯放在了那里
that's where he had stashed that diamond bracelet.
我爱死这一刻了
Oh, I love this part--
肾上腺素激增
The kick of adrenaline,
心跳加快
the quickening of the heart,
期望即将实现
those last few drops of anticipation.
是空的
It's empty.
那手镯在哪
So where is the bracelet?
不管它在哪  一定在嘲笑我
Wherever it is, it's laughing at me.
也许马可搞错了
Maybe Marco was wrong,
温德尔死前就把手镯出手了
and Wendell sold it before he was killed.
那卖手镯的钱去哪了
Well, then where's the money from the sale?
没有钱说明手镯应该还在
No money means there should be a bracelet.
没有手镯说明应该有钱
No bracelet means there should be money.
我觉得我们应该问的问题是  温德尔是怎么
I think the question we should be asking is, how did Wendell
开始实施这个盗窃计划的
even pull off a heist like this to begin with?
安吉莉卡说小偷弄开了壁式保险箱
Angelica said that the thief cracked the wall safe.
你知道弄开壁式保险箱得有多难吗
Do you know how hard it is to crack a wall safe?
特别考虑到温德尔的储物仓库里都没有
Especially since Wendell didn't even have
任何适合的工具  这...
any of the proper equipment in his storage unit. It just--
说不通吗
Doesn't make any sense?
谢谢
Thank you.
除非安吉莉卡没有跟我们说实话
Unless Angelica wasn't telling us the truth.
看看这个
Listen to this--
一周前安吉莉卡本应出席破产听证会
Angelica was scheduled for a bankruptcy hearing a week ago,
但是听证会被取消了  因为她向债权人
but it was canceled because she made a $2-million payment
支付了两百万
to her creditors.
恰好是在保险公司赔偿了她
That's right after the insurance company
手镯的赔偿金之后
paid her claim on the bracelet.
如果整件事情
What if this whole thing
是有预谋的保险诈骗呢
was a ploy to commit insurance fraud?
"任务完成"
"Mission accomplished."
温德尔入室成功后是这么说的
That's what Wendell said after the break-in.
"任务完成"
"Mission accomplished."
没错  他没说他到底要偷什么
Right. He didn't say he actually stole anything.
任务就是要制造出盗窃的假象
The mission was to make it look like a robbery.
而制造假象
And the best way to make it look real,
欺骗警察和保险公司的最佳办法
to fool the police and the insurance company...
就是真的入室但却不偷任何东西
Is to actually break in yet steal nothing.
安吉莉卡设计了这整件事
Angelica set this whole thing up.
唯一的知情人就是温德尔
And the only other person that knew was Wendell.
她无法承担那对姐弟泄露秘密的风险
She couldn't afford to let him or his sister expose her secret.
我认为那算杀人动机
I call that motive for murder
可以据此申请搜查令
and probable cause for a search warrant.
干得好
Good work.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉  亨利女士  他们硬闯进来的
I'm sorry, Ms. Henley. They just barged in.
我试过阻止他们
I tried to stop them.
你们没有理由搜查我的住所
You people have no grounds to search my residence.
事实上  我们有
Actually... we do.
这真令人发指
This is outrageous.
没错  确实令人发指
She's right. This is outrageous.
知道你应该做什么吗
You know what you should do?
打开壁式保险箱  证明我们是错的
Open that wall safe and prove us wrong.
好吧  如果你想  我们也能从墙里撬出来
Fine. We can just tear it out of the wall if you'd like.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
在里面吗
Well, is it there?
你好  尤物
Hello, gorgeous.
这件小美物可惹了不少麻烦  不是吗
This little beauty has caused a lot of trouble, hasn't it?
美丽的东西就会这样  亲爱的
That's what beautiful things do, my dear,
至少我是这么认为的
at least to me.
那为什么你不把它卖了
So why didn't you just sell it
以解决所有的财政问题
and solve all your money problems
而是雇温德尔伪造一起盗窃案
instead of hiring Wendell to stage a robbery?
我没雇温德尔
I didn't hire Wendell.
你告诉我之前  我甚至不知道
I didn't even know he was involved in all of this
他也牵扯在内
until you told me.
就是说他入室当晚  你打电话报警
So the fact that he broke in the same night that you called
说手镯被偷了
and reported this stolen,
也只是个巧合吗
that's just a coincidence?
当我回到家
Look, when I came home
看见公寓被盗之后
and saw that my apartment had been burglarized,
我恐慌至极  震惊万分
I was-- I was panicked, shocked.
但我发现没有东西被偷
Until I saw that nothing had been taken.
于是我想不如
So I thought that if I
就假装自己的手镯被盗
simply pretended that my bracelet had been stolen,
这样能解决我所有的问题
it would solve all my problems.
可你又制造出了两个新问题
Except you created two new problems--
你的司机和他的姐姐
your chauffer and his sister--
都死了
both of whom are now dead.
我想我该加律师来了
I think it's time for me to call my attorney.
她认了保险诈骗罪
So she admitted to insurance fraud
希望能避免谋杀的指控
hoping to avoid murder charges.
至少我觉得这是她玩的戏码
At least I think that's her play.
-你觉得  -对  她是个绝望的女人
- You think? - Yeah, she's a desperate woman
面临着即将失去的所有财富
on the verge of losing her wealth.
这无疑是对她判了死刑
That's death to someone like her.
她会愿意做任何事来避免这样
She's probably willing to do anything to avoid it--
比如撒谎  偷窃  诈骗
lie, steal, cheat,
甚至谋杀
and in this case, kill.
对  但那仍无法解释储物仓库的事
Yeah, but that still doesn't explain the storage locker.
如果温德尔没有偷任何东西
I mean, if Wendell didn't steal anything,
那他往里面放了什么
what did he put in there
会让他姐姐这么渴望拿到手
that his sister was so desperate to get?
而且如果这和她的谋杀案无关
And if it didn't have anything to do with her murder,
她为什么要用自己的血写下那个仓库号
why would she write the locker number in her blood?
卡塞尔  你仔细地
Castle, you went through that storage unit
检查了仓库里的东西
with a fine-tooth comb.
你说里面没有任何有价值的东西
You said that there's nothing of value in there.
没错  对我们来说没有价值
Well, yeah, nothing of value to us.
但如果对他们来说有价值呢
But I mean, what about something of value to them?
比如说
Like what?
我不知道  小饰品
I don't know-- a trinket,
或是传家宝
an heirloom.
答案就在那里的某处  一定在
The answer's in there somewhere. It has to be.
总之  时间不早了
Anyway... It's getting late.
明天第一件事是送阿丽克西斯去学校
I have to drop off Alexis first thing in the morning.
-明天再重新开始吧  -好
- Fresh start tomorrow? - Sure.
要送你出去吗
Walk you out?
我再待一会儿
Uh, you know what? I've gotta stick around.
我要再查一下安吉莉卡的不在场证词
I have to go over Angelica's alibi.
好吧
All right.
此刻我真希望能吻你
I so wish I could kiss you right now.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
这是我...
This is me...
轻柔地触碰你的脸庞
softly touching your face,
拥你入怀  深情一吻
pulling you in for a long, slow kiss.
这是我在回吻你
And this is me kissing you back,
我的手指拂过你的头发
running my hands through your hair.
这是最美好的握手
Best handshake ever.
没错
Yeah.
我的手好像出汗了
I think my hand's getting a little sweaty.
我知道  有点恶心
I know. It's kinda gross.
-抱歉  -没关系
- Sorry. - No worries.
阿丽克西斯
Oh, Alexis.
亲爱的  永别了
My darling, farewell.
天知道我们何时能再次相见
God knows when we shall meet again.
莎士比亚说的  你知道吗
That's Shakespeare, you know?
我知道
I know.
好了  不说永别  不说再见
All right, no farewells, no good-byes.
过会儿见  孩子
Just see ya later, kiddo.
过会儿见  奶奶
See you later, gram.
我在大厅等你  亲爱的
I'll be in the hall, darling.
好的
All right.
那个...
So...
这里就是你的新家了吗
This is your new home, huh?
听着  我理解
Hey, look, I get it.
真的
I do.
但无论我和贝克特之间发生了什么事
But whatever happens between Beckett and me,
我想让你知道  我们可能明天就分手
I want you to know-- I mean, we could break up tomorrow,
也可能会一起共度余生
we could spend the rest of our lives together--
但她绝不会取代你在我心中的位置
but she will never take your place in my heart.
我为什么要担心贝克特警探会取代我
Why would I be worried about detective Beckett replacing me?
你当时表现得...  我以为
You were act-- I thought--
你是怎么做到智慧和愚蠢并重的
How can you be so smart and so clueless at the same time?
多练练就好了
Practice.
跟贝克特没什么关系
This is no more about Beckett
我就是觉得我妈怎么能不来
than it's about the fact my mother isn't here.
-对不起  亲爱的  你妈她  -不
- Sorry, honey, but your mom... - No.
-她在  -没关系
- She's in-- - No, it's fine.
真的没关系
It's always been fine,
因为不管怎么样
because no matter what,
我醒来时你都会在我旁边
I'd wake up, and you'd be there,
让我知道一切安好
and I'd know that everything's fine.
现在你要住在这里了...
Oh, and when you wake up here...
没错
Then I'm here.
而你不在
And you're there.
虽然从家到这里只有五英里
Even though there is only 5 miles away...
这里毕竟跟家不一样
it's not here.
一切都会没事的
Well, everything is going to be fine.
你也是
And you are gonna be fine.
虽然我不在你身边
And though I am there,
只要你需要
if you need me here,
我就会马上来
here is where I'll be.
爸
Hey, dad.
我知道这是很久以前的事了  不过
I-I know it's been a while, but, um...
你能不能再来...
could you do it...
最后一次
one last time?
没有小怪兽
No monsters.
确定吗
You sure?
确定  有的话我一定跑来救你
Yeah, and if there are, I'll come running.
亲爱的  你在哭吗
Darling, are you crying?
没有  过敏而已
No, it's allergies.
花粉太多
The pollen count is high.
我也花粉过敏了
The pollen count's gotten to me, too.
-是吧  -我知道
- Right? - I know.
你能自己回家吧
You can get home by yourself, right?
-我  -谢啦  爱你  老妈
- Well, I-- - Thanks. Love you, mother.
我知道在哪了
I know where it is.
什么在哪
Where what is?
不知道是什么东西  只知道它在哪
I don't know what it is, only where it is.
温德尔偷的东西只对自己
Whatever Wendell stole was only of value to him
和他的孪生姐姐有价值
and his twin sister.
所以他只会把东西藏在
So he would hide it in the one place
她会去找的地方
only she would look.
温蒂  温德尔  孪生
Wendy, Wendell, twins--
尽在双子娃娃收藏
as in gemini collectibles.
就是它了
This is it.
卡塞尔
Castle!
空的
It's empty.
这不可能
Oh, that can't be right.
-怎么  -长官  呼吸
- What-- - Oh, sir, just breathe.
你到底干了什么
What the hell have you done?
我以为
I thought--
你以为什么  卡塞尔先生
Y-you thought what, Mr. Castle?
我以为温德尔会把他偷来的东西
I just thought that Wendell would've hidden what he stole
-放在双子  -这不是温德尔的那个  是我的
- inside the gemini-- - It wasn't Wendell's. It was mine!
我早上刚从家里带来的
I brought it in from home this morning!
好吧  我的错
All right, that's my bad.
等等  这说明
Wait. That means...
原来在这儿
Ah. Here it is.
别  别  不
D-d-d--No!
一个U盘跟一只玻璃假眼
A U.S.B. drive and a glass eye.
我没想到会是这些东西
I didn't see that coming.
U盘里的照片都是在
Okay, so the photos from this U.S.B. drive
犯罪现场拍的
are from a crime scene.
哪里的犯罪现场
A crime scene where?
宾夕法尼亚的摩西
Mercer, Pennsylvania.
照片大约摄于十年前  是一起肇事逃逸事故
They're about a decade old. It was a hit-and-run.
这些跟一只玻璃假眼有什么关系
What does any of this have to do with a glass eye?
这对双胞胎的父母
Weren't the twins' parents
不是十年前死于一场车祸吗
killed in a car crash ten years ago?
没错  他们被别的车撞了下车尾
Yeah, they were rear-ended,
导致整辆车掉下了路堤
and their car went down an embankment.
报告上说他们被困在车里  失血过多而亡
Report said that they were trapped inside and bled out,
如果肇事车停下来打电话求救
and that if the person who hit them would've stopped
他们或许还能活下来
and called for help, they might have lived.
大伙  注意看照片
Hey, guys. Look at this photo.
这也是犯罪现场的照片  一只破碎的玻璃假眼
It's from the crime scene, and it's of a broken glass eye.
什么
What?
玻璃假眼
A glass eye?
等等
Wait a minute.
现在一切都说得通了
Of course. It all makes sense now.
是吗
It does?
温德尔的痴迷
Wendell's obsession--
他为什么会不断搬家
why he moved from place to place,
为什么来到纽约  为什么用假名
why he came to New York, why he used a fake name
还有一本有关假体眼球的书
and a had a book on prosthetic eyes.
他在执行任务
He was-- he was on a mission.
什么任务
Yeah, but on a mission to do what?
找到害死自己父母的凶手
Well, to find the person responsible for his parents' death.
为了确认身份
In order to be sure,
温德尔不得不去偷嫌疑人的假眼
Wendell had to steal the suspect's glass eye.
所以才入室偷盗
That's what the heist was about.
就跟对比指纹一样  他拿这张照片去对比假眼
And like fingerprints, he used that photo to compare the eyes.
就像理查德·金布尔一样
A la Richard Kimble,
不过他要找的不是一个装义肢的男人
but instead of looking for a one-armed man...
而是一个装了假眼球的人
He was looking for a one-eyed man.
或者应该说  一个装了假眼球的女人
Or in our case, a one-eyed woman.
除非律师在场  否则我不会说半个字
I'm not saying a word without my lawyer.
你不用说话  听着就行
You don't have to, but you might want to listen.
我们知道了温德尔偷了什么
We know what Wendell stole.
我受够了  我要叫律师
That's it. I'm calling my attorney.
能让我来吗
Uh, may I?
-好吧  -谢谢
- Yes. - Thank you.
我协助过很多谋杀案
I've worked a lot of murder cases,
耐心地等待着
waiting patiently for the day
有一天能明确地高呼
I could unequivocally exclaim,
凶手就是管家
The butler did it.
什么
What?
你肯定很震惊
Must have been a shock--
这么多年过去了
All these years later,
你终于能够摆脱一切
after you put all that behind you,
可这个人突然出现
to have someone walk into your life
又把你的生活全部打乱
and stir it all back up again.
科比
Kirby.
他在说什么
What's he talking about?
你的管家交通肇事
Your live-in butler caused a car accident
还逃离现场
and then fled the scene.
两人因他的逃逸而丧命
Because he did, two people lost their lives.
而这两人就是温德尔的父母
And those people were Wendell's parents.
这简直
That is...
荒谬至极
absolutely ridiculous.
你根本没有证据
You can't prove any of it.
温德尔偷走的假眼上有你的DNA
Your D.N.A. was on the prosthetic eye that Wendell stole.
与在温蒂旅馆房间
And it's a match to the D.N.A.
发现的弹壳上的DNA相吻合
found on the shell casing in Wendy's hotel room.
都结束了
It's all over.
我那么努力
I worked...
想要忘记那个晚上
so hard to put that night--
那个可怕的晚上
that horrible night-- behind me.
而那次入室盗窃
And then the break-in.
有那么多东西可以偷
Of all the things to steal,
却偏偏拿走了我抽屉里的备用假眼
my spare eye from off my bureau.
那时我才弄明白
That's when I put it all together--
那个新来司机真正的身份
who the new chauffer truly was
以及他想要证明的事情
and what he was trying to prove.
但你  你们也得理解
But you-- you have to understand...
我无法使他们的父母起死回生
I couldn't bring their parents back.
这不可能
I-I couldn't.
我为什么要遭这个罪
Why should I suffer?
科比·史密斯  你因谋杀
Kirby Smith, you're under arrest
温德尔和温蒂·杜普利
for the murders of Wendell
而被捕
and Wendy Dupree.
我相信宾夕法尼亚州政府
And I am sure that the state of Pennsylvania
一定还会再为你加上两条
will be adding two counts
驾车过失杀人罪
of vehicular manslaughter to that.
科比对其罪行供认不讳
Kirby made a full confession.
他曾读到一篇关于近期一起
He read an article about a recent mugging
地铁站抢劫案件的文章
in the subway station,
决定在那里杀了温德尔
and decided to kill Wendell there.
因为他知道那里的摄像头坏了
Because he knew that the cameras wouldn't be working.
但温德尔偷走的证据依然存在
But the evidence that Wendell stole
他的妹妹温蒂也同样知情
was still out there, so was his sister Wendy.
当她去往仓库
When she started poking around storage spaces,
科比跟踪她回旅馆并枪杀了她
Kirby tracked her to the hotel and shot her.
卑鄙的混蛋
Worthless bastard.
你说什么
I'm sorry.
他毁了他们全家
He took out their whole family.
干得好  探长
Good job, detective.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在...她又讨厌我了
And... she hates me again.
是啊  看来那些娃娃对她十分重要
Yeah, well, those gemini dolls obviously meant a lot to her.
我好奇背后的故事
Yeah, I wonder what that story is.
我好奇背后的所有故事
I wonder what those stories are.
那堆东西你打算怎么处理  卡塞尔
What are you gonna do with all of that stuff, Castle?
我打算把登山装备送给哈维尔
Well, I'll give the climbing equipment to Javier,
另外的嘛
and then, uh,
我想我会都捐了吧
donate the rest, I guess.
它们已经完成了使命  为他们家伸张了正义
It served its purpose. Brought justice to his family.
但同样也说明每个人
But it just goes to show you that everyone
每件东西背后都有一个故事
and everything has a story,
包括你的小人
Including your little stick man there.
那么
So...
你还要再试试吗
You want to take another shot?
不了
Actually, no.
我仔细想了想你的话
I thought about what you said.
你说的没错
And you're right.
就算我们已经...
Just because we've been...
"握手"
Shaking hands
很多次
a lot...
但也不意味着我就有权力窥探
Doesn't mean that I have the right to pry.
所以  等你做好准备
So... when you are ready,
你会告诉我的
you'll tell me.
科尼岛
Coney Island.
在我妈妈的葬礼之后
We, uh, we had a reception at our place
我们家有个招待
after my mom's funeral,
非常痛苦
and... it was miserable.
我非常痛苦  我爸爸
I was miserable, and my dad...
握着我的手说
took my hand and he said, uh,
我们一起离开这里吧  凯特
"Let's get the hell outta here, Katie."
于是我们搭上Q号地铁
And we took the "Q" Train,
来到了科尼岛
and we went up to Coney Island.
我们在海边散步
And we walked up and down that beach,
享受生活
just enjoying ourselves.
我们依然穿着葬礼时的衣服
We were still in our funeral clothes.
最值得纪念的就是这个
And the best part was that we made this little guy
我们用冲上岸的树枝扎成的小人
Out of the twigs and twine that washed up on the shore.
这使那天成为了
Does that make that day
你愉快还是不愉快的回忆呢
a bad memory or a good one?
都有吧
Both.
它提醒我
He's a reminder...
即便是在最糟糕的日子里
that even on the worst days,
也有快乐的可能
there's a possibility for joy.
真好
Nice.
我们今晚再聊吗
So we'll talk tonight?
等你
I can't wait.
我的小姑娘
My little girl.
阿丽克西斯搬走了使我不禁想了很久
Alexis' moving out got me to thinking.
经过多时的自我反省
And after many hours of soul searching,
我做了一个决定
I have made a decision.
-是吗  -没错
- Have you now? - Yes.
出于我的好心  我决定
I have decided, out of the goodness of my heart,
我会继续住在这里
that I will continue to live here--
免房租
Rent-free.
别插嘴
Please don't interrupt.
我会继续住在这里
I will continue to live here
这样你  理查德
So that you, Richard...
就永远不会孤单
will never, ever be alone.
你这是为了我吗  妈妈
You'd do that for me, mother?
这叫为人母的牺牲
It's a parent's sacrifice.